Guide to the Dutchess County Loyalists Papers, 1776-1922
Archives and Special Collections Library, Vassar College Libraries
Dutchess County Loyalists Papers
1776-1922
1 box (0.5 cubic feet )
Archives and Special Collections Library, Vassar College Libraries
Letters and legal documents regarding Loyalist residents of Dutchess County and Poughkeepsie, NY, during and immediately after the American Revolution; transcripts and descriptions of materials by Albany, NY, dealer Pierre and Scropes, Inc.; photocopies of original documents.
Historical Note
During the American Revolution (1775-1783) those who remained loyal to Great Britain often found themselves threatened and forced to flee their homes by their Patriot neighbors. Many who fled made new homes in the Canadian maritime provinces of New Brunswick and Nova Scotia. Before fleeing, Loyalists frequently petitioned the Crown for aid and, after the Revolution, undertook legal proceedings to gain compensation for property they lost when they left. The materials in this collection document the experience of a number of Loyalists who lived in Dutchess County, NY, and ultimately fled to New Brunswick.
Scope and Content Note
Letters and legal documents regarding Loyalist residents of Dutchess County and Poughkeepsie, NY, during and immediately after the American Revolution; transcripts and descriptions of materials by Albany, NY, dealer Pierre and Scropes, Inc.; photocopies of original documents.
Access
This collection is open for research according to the
regulations of the Vassar College Archives and Special Collections Library
without any additional restrictions.
Subject Headings
Subjects:
American loyalists--New York (State)--Dutchess County
Places:
Dutchess County (N.Y.)--History--1775-1865--Sources; Poughkeepsie (N.Y.)--History--1775-1865--Sources; New York (State)--History--1775-1865--Sources
VCL Categories
Local History
Encoding Information
Encoded by Mark Seidl, March 2014. Updated by Mark Seidl, May 2014.
Acquisition Information
Purchased from Pierre and Scropes, Inc., June 1922. Transferred from Special Collections Dewey material, March 2014.
Arrangement
This collection is arranged in two series, and alphabetically within each series.
Series List
- Series I. Original Documents, 1776-1786
- Series II. Dealer's Materials, circa 1920
  This series includes the materials provided by the dealer Pierre and Scropes, Inc., including enclosures, transcripts of the documents, and photocopies of the documents and transcripts.
Container List
- Series I. Original Documents
  - Appointment of Gilbert Livingston as attorny for John Beardsley, 1789 (Folder 1.1)
  - Descent of B. Crannell, circa 1785 (Folder 1.2)
  - Letter from Mr. Crannell to his sons-in-law Gilbert and Tappan, 1785 (Folder 1.3)
  - Letter from Reverend John Beardsley to Gilbert Livingston, 1786 (Folder 1.4)
  - Petition of the faithful subjects of his Majesty King Geo. the third, 1776 (Folder 1.5)
  - Schedule of real estate, circa 1785 (Folder 1.6)
- Series II. Dealer's Materials
  - Dealer's description of Five Poughkeepsie Loyalists documents, circa 1922; [original ms. and photocopy] (Folder 1.7)
  - Dealer's description of Petition of the faithful subjects.. ., circa 1922; [original ms. and photocopy] (Folder 1.8)
  - Dealer's enclosure for Five Poughkeepsie Loyalists documents, circa 1922; [includes typed description] (Folder 1.9)
  - Dealer's enclosure for Petition of the faithful subjects.. ., circa 1922; [includes typed description] (Folder 1.10)
  - Photocopies, circa 1922 (Folder 1.11)
  - Typed transcript of Petition of the faithful subjects.. ., circa 1922 (Folder 1.12)